Temple, Nelson, Lloyd, Vassall, and Borland family papers (bMS Am 1250): Guide.
Temple, Nelson, Lloyd, Vassall, and Borland family papers,
- V. Correspondence of Senator James Lloyd
  - Boston, Citizens. Printed from filled out in MS., s. by Charles Bulfinch; Boston, 9 May 1805., (209); 1s.(2p.)
    Notice of election of James Lloyd to the General Court.
  - Boston, Trinity church. MS.L.(s. by Samuel D. Parker) to James Lloyd; Boston, 23 Apr 1827., (210); 1s.(2p.)
  - Bradford, Alden, 1765-1843. A.L.s. to [James Lloyd]; [n.p., n.d.], (211); 1s.(4p.)
    Contains transcript of Chief Justice Parker's description of Castine, Maine.
  - Breck, Samuel, 1771-1862. 3 A.L.s. to James Lloyd, as follows:
    - Sweetbriar, 14 Oct 1824., (212); 1s.(4p.)
    - Same, 14 Oct 1825., (213); 1s.(3p.)
    - Same, 5 Jun 1828., (214); 1s.(4p.)
    - Same, MS. (modern transcript) = Extracts from the diaries of Samuel Breck., (215); 8s.(8p.)
  - Bridge, James. A.L.s. to James Lloyd; Augusta, Ms., 20 Jul 1818., (216); 1s.(2p.)
  - Brooks, John, 1752-1825. 3 A.L.s. to James Lloyd, as follows:
    - Medford, 20 Dec 1816., (217); 1s.(4p.)
    - Same, 17 Jan 1817., (218); 1s.(3p.)
    - Same, 21 Feb 1817., (219); 1s.(4p.)
  - Brooks, John. A.L.s. to Caleb Strong; Boston, 1 Oct 1814., (220); 1s.(3p.)
  - Calhoun, John Caldwell, 1782-1850. MS.L.s. to James Lloyd; [Washington] 4 May 1824., (221); 1s.(2p.)
  - Calhoun, John Caldwell, 1782-1850. MS.L.s. to George Sullivan; [Washington] 21 Feb 1825., (222); 1s.(2p.)
  - Clough, Ebenezer. A.L.s. to James Lloyd; Boston, 26 Jun 1826., (223); 1s.(2p.)
  - Dearborn, Henry, 1751-1829. 2 A.L.s. to John Brooks, as follows:
    - Boston, 12 Aug 1814., (224); 1s.(2p.)
    - Same, 6 Sep 1814., (225); 1s.(2p.)
  - Dearborn, Henry, 1751-1829. A.L.s. to Thomas Handasyd Perkins; Fort Independence, 25 Sep 1814., (226); 1s.(4p.)
  - English, George Bethune, 1787-1828. A.L.s. to James Lloyd; [n.p.] 28 Sep 1812., (227); 1s.(2p.)
  - English, Thomas. A.L.s. to James Lloyd; Boston, 2 Feb 1809., (228); 1s.(4p.)
  - Eustis, William, 1753-1825. 11 A.L.s. to James Lloyd, as follows:
    - [Boston] 7 Jul 1823., (229); 1s.(2p.)
    - [Same, 20 Jul 1823], (230); 1s.(2p.)
    - [Same] 27 Jul [1823], (231); 1s.(2p.)
    - Roxbury, 2 Nov 1823., (232); 1s.(2p.)
    - Same, 24 Nov 1823., (233); 1s.(2p.)
    - Boston, 17 Jan 1824., (234); 1s.(2p.)
    - Roxbury, 24 Feb 1824., (235); 1s.(2p.)
    - Same, 23 Mar 1824., (236); 1s.(2p.)
    - Same, 17 May 1824., (237); 1s.(2p.)
    - [Same] 10 Nov 1824., (238); 1s.(2p.)
    - Same, 20 Dec 1824., (239); 1s.(4p.)
  - Everett, Edward, 1794-1865. A.L.s. to James Lloyd, as follows:
    - Cambridge, 8 Dec 1823., (240); 1s.(3p.)
    - Same, 20 Dec 1823., (241); 1s.(4p.)
    - Boston, 1 Sep 1824., (242); 1s.(2p.)
      printed form filled out in MS.
    - Same, 2 Oct 1824., (243); 1s.(2p.)
    - Cambridge, 5 Oct 1824., (244); 1s.(2p.)
  - Fitch, Ann. A.L.s. to [Sarah (Comrin) Lloyd?]; London, 18 Jan 1780., (245); 1s.(4p.)
  - Fitch, Ann. 7 A.L.s. to James Lloyd, as follows:
    - [London?] 16 Feb 1813., (246); 1s.(4p.)
    - [Same?] 19 Jul 1813., (247); 1s.(4p.)
    - Sodbury, 27 Jun 1820., (248); 1s.(4p.)
    - [Same] 22 Feb 1822., (249); 1s.(4p.)
    - Same, 3 Sep 1825., (250); 1s.(4p.)
    - [Same, 4 Mar 1828], (251); 1s.(4p.)
    - Same, 26 Mar 1831., (252); 2s.(8p.)
  - Forbes, John Murray, 1771-1831. MS.L.s. to James Lloyd; Copenhagen, 20 Jan 1813., (253); 1s.(4p.)
  - Fulton, Robert, 1765-1815. A.L.s. to James Lloyd; New York, 8 May 1812., (254); 1s.(2p.)
    Enclosing autograph petition of Fulton to Congress, 1s.(2p.)
  - Gardiner, John Sylvester John, 1765-1830. A.L.s. to James Lloyd; Boston, 20 Apr 1827., (255); 1s.(3p.)
  - Gray, John Chipman, 1793-1881. A.L.s. to James Lloyd; [n.p.] 17 Jul 1827., (256); 1s.(4p.)
    Extensively annotated by Lloyd.
  - Greene, Gardiner. 2 A.L.s. to James Lloyd, as follows:
    - Boston, 23 Nov 1823., (257); 1s.(2p.)
    - Same, 14 Feb 1825., (258); 1s.(3p.)
  - Greenleaf, Moses, 1777-1834. A.L.s. to Alden Bradford; Boston, 24 Dec 1816., (259); 1s.(4p.)
  - Greenleaf, Moses, 1777-1834. A.L.s. to James Lloyd; Boston, 24 Dec 1816., (260); 1s.(4p.)
    Both letters deal with the condition of Castine.
  - Hall, Joseph. A.L.s. to James Lloyd; Boston, 31 Jan 1809., (261); 1s.(3p.)
  - Hamilton, Alexander. A.L.s. to James Lloyd; New York, 20 Aug 1824., (262); 1s.(2p.)
  - Harris, Levett. A.L.s. to James Lloyd; Philadelphia, 14 Apr 1826., (263); 1s.(3p.)
  - Hillhouse, James Abraham, 1789-1841. A.L.s. to Sarah Borland; New York, 3 Aug 1816., (264); 1s.(3p.)
  - Hillhouse, James Abraham, 1789-1841. 3 A.L.s. to James Lloyd, as follows:
    - New York, 12 Jan 1818., (625); 1s.(2p.)
    - Same, 5 Apr 1822., (266); 1s.(2p.)
    - Same, 1 May 1827., (267); 1s.(4p.)
  - Hillhouse, Mary Lucas, 1785-1871. A.L.s. to James Lloyd; New Haven, 24 Apr 1827., (268); 1s.(4p.)
  - Hunter, William, 1774-1849. A.L.s. to James Lloyd; Washington, 16 Jul 1813., (269); 1s.(2p.)
  - Jackson, Andrew, pres. U. S., 1767-1845. A.L.s. to James Lloyd; Hermitage, 14 Jul 1826., (270); 1s.(4p.)
  - Jarvis, William Charles, d. 1836. 2 A.L.s. to James Lloyd, as follows:
    - Pittsfield, 19 Dec 1822., (271); 1s.(3p.)
    - Same, 22 Feb 1823., (272); 1s.(4p.)
  - King, William, 1768-1852. 4 A.L.s. to John Brooks, as follows:
    - Bath, Me., 24 Jun 1814., (273); 2s.(6p.)
    - Same, 27 Jun 1814., (274); 1s.(4p.)
    - Same, 8 Jul 1814., (275); 1s.(4p.)
    - Belfast, 8 Sep 1814., (276); 1s.(4p.)
  - King, William, 1768-1852., (277); 1s.(4p.)
    MS.L.(copy) to John Chandler; Wiscasset, 19 Sep 1814. 1s.(3p.)
  - King, William, 1768-1852., (278); 1s.(4p.)
    A.L.s. to James Lloyd; Bath, 28 Sep 1823. 1s.(3p.)
  - Knight, Anna. A.L.s. to James Lloyd; Somerset, 24 Oct 1809., (279); 1s.(2p.)
  - Lafayette, Marie Joseph Paul Yves Roch Gilbert du Motier, marquis de, 1757-1834. 12 A.L.s. to James Lloyd, as follows:
    - Paris, 29 May 1824., (280); 1s.(2p.)
    - La Grange, 11 Sep 1824., (281); 1s.(2p.)
    - New York, 20 Sep 1824., (282); 1s.(2p.)
  - Lafayette, Marie Joseph Paul Yves Roch Gilbert du Motier, marquis de, 1757-1834. 12 A.L.s. to James Lloyd, as follows:
    - [Washington, 8 Dec 1824], (283); 1s.(2p.)
    - Albany, 12 Jun 1825., (284); 1s.(2p.)
    - [N.p.] 21 Jun 1825., (285); 1s.(2p.)
    - New York, 13 Jul 1825., (286); 1s.(2p.)
    - Philadelphia, 24 Jul 1825., (287); 1s.(2p.)
    - Paris, 26 Feb 1826., (288); 1s.(3p.)
    - Same, 29 Mar 1826., (289); 1s.(1p.)
    - Same, 22 Mar 1827., (290); 1s.(2p.)
    - La Grange, 10 Jan 1829., (291); 1s.(3p.)
  - Lincoln, Levi, 1782-1868. 2 A.L.s. to James Lloyd, as follows:
    - Boston, 7 Oct 1825., (292); 1s.(3p.)
    - [Worcester, Oct 1825], (293); 1s.(2p.)
  - Livingston, John W. A.L.s. to James Lloyd; Albany, 23 Jan 1825., (294); 1s.(3p.)
  - Lloyd, Hannah (Breck) d. 1846. [Printed obituary notice of Hannah (Breck) Lloyd] Addressed in MS. by Samuel Breck to Sarah D. Coit; Philadelphia, [ ] Nov 1846., (295); 1s.(1p.)
  - Lloyd, James, 1769-1831. [Obituary notice on James Lloyd] MS.(unidentified hand); [n.p., 1831], (296)
  - Lloyd, John Nelson. 9 A.L.s. to James Lloyd, as follows:
    - New York, 9 Jul 1813., (297); 1s.(2p.)
    - Lloyd's Neck, 13 Apr 1822., (298); 1s.(4p.)
    - Same, 5 Mar 1823., (299); 1s.(4p.)
    - Same, 8 Dec 1823., (300); 1s.(4p.)
    - Same, 16 Jan 1824., (301); 1s.(2p.)
    - Same, 28 Aug 1824., (302); 1s.(4p.)
    - Same, 25 Feb 1827., (303); 2s.(6p.)
    - Same, 8 Mar 1829., (304); 1s.(4p.)
    - Same, 2 Jul 1829., (305); 1s.(4p.)
  - Loring, Robert R. A.L.s. to James Lloyd; Montreal, 5 Sep 1822., (306); 1s.(3p.)
  - McLane, Allan, 1746-1829. A.L.s. to Callender Irving; Wilmington, Del., 25 Feb 1813., (307); 1s.(3p.)
  - Maine. Militia. MS.L. to Alford Richardson; Portland, 24 Sep 1814., (308); 2s.(8p.)
  - Massachusetts. Council. [Resolution to appoint commissioners for the protection of Boston harbor] MS. (unidentified hand); Boston, 16 Jun 1814., (309); 1s.(4p.)
  - Massachusetts. Governor, 1825-1833 (Levi Lincoln) MS.L.(s. by Edward D. Rangs, secy.) to James Lloyd; Boston, 1 Jul 1826., (310); 1s.(2p.)
  - Otis, Harrison Gray, 1765-1848. 2 A.L.s. to James Lloyd, as follows:
    - Boston, 7 Nov 1816., (311); 1s.(4p.)
    - Same, 11 Nov 1816., (312); 1s.(4p.)
  - Parker, Daniel, 1782-1846. A.L.s. to James Lloyd; Washington, 4 May 1823., (313); 1s.(3p.)
  - Parker, Isaac, 1768-1830. A.L.s. to James Lloyd; Boston, 23 Dec 1816., (314); 1s.(4p.)
  - Parker, John. 2 A.L.s. to James Lloyd, as follows:
    - Boston, 1 May 1828., (315); 1s.(3p.)
    - Same, 20 Jan 1831., (316); 1s.(3p.)
  - Peake, H. A.L.s. to James Lloyd; [Washington, 18 May 181-?], (317); 1s.(3p.)
    With draft of Lloyd's reply.
  - Perkins, Thomas Handasyd, 1764-1854. 8 A.L.s. to James Lloyd, as follows:
    - [Boston] 16 Feb [1809], (318); 1s.(4p.)
    - [Same] 4 Nov 1812., (319); 1s.(2p.)
    - [Same, 1813], (320); 1s.(2p.)
    - Same, 26 May 1820., (321); 1s.(4p.)
    - [Same] 29 Oct [1822], (322); 1s.(3p.)
    - Same, 4 Dec 1822., (323); 1s.(2p.)
    - [Same?] 8 Oct 1823., (324); 1s.(2p.)
    - Same, 18 Feb 1828., (325); 1s.(2p.)
  - Pickman, Benjamin, 1763-1843. 5 A.L.s. to James Lloyd, as follows:
    - Salem, 27 Dec 1819., (326); 2s.(6p.)
    - Same, 8 Dec 1823., (327); 2s.(6p.)
    - Same, 16 Feb 1824., (328); 1s.(4p.)
    - Same, 19 May 1824., (329); 1s.(4p.)
    - Same, 8 Oct 1825., (330); 1s.(3p.)
  - Prime, Nathaniel. 4 A.L.s. to James Lloyd, as follows:
    - New York, 18 Oct 1822., (331); 1s.(4p.)
    - Hell Gate, 10 May 1823., (332); 1s.(4p.)
    - Same, 4 Aug 1825., (333); 1s.(3p.)
    - New York, 29 May 1827., (334); 1s.(3p.)
  - Quincy, Josiah, 1772-1864. A.L.s. to James Lloyd; [Boston] 9 Apr 1822., (335); 1s.(2p.)
  - Raguet, Condy, 1784-1842. A.L.s. to James Lloyd; Rio de Janeiro, 25 May 1823., (336); 2s.(8p.)
  - Randolph, John, 1773-1833. 17 A.L.s. to James Lloyd, as follows:
    - Philadelphia, 16 Dec 1814., (337); 1s.(2p.)
    - [N.p., 15 Mar 1826], (338); 1s.(2p.)
      in pencil.
    - [N.p., 18 Mar 1826], (339); 1s.(4p.)
    - [N.p., 18 Mar 1826], (340); 1s.(2p.)
    - [N.p.] 21 Mar 1826., (341); 1s.(2p.)
    - [N.p.] 8 Apr 1826., (342); 1s.(2p.)
    - [N.p., 5 May 1826], (343); 2s.(6p.)
    - [N.p., 7 May 1826], (344); 1s.(2p.)
    - [N.p.] 24 Dec 1827., (345); 1s.(2p.)
    - Georgetown, 24 Feb [1817? 1823?], (346); 1s.(1p.)
    - [N.p., n.d.], (347); 1s.(3p.)
    - [N.p., n.d.], (348); 1s.(3p.)
    - [N.p., n.d.], (349); 1s.(2p.)
    - [N.p., n.d.], (350); 1s.(1p.)
    - [N.p., n.d.], (351); 1s.(2p.)
    - [N.p., n.d.], (352); 1s.(3p.)
    - 3 covers from letters directed by Randolph to Lloyd., (353); 3s.(3p.)
  - Reynolds, Edward, 1793-1881. A.L.s. to James Lloyd; Boston, 3 Dec 1826., (354); 1s.(4p.)
  - Rush, Richard, 1780-1859. A.L.s. to James Lloyd; Washington, 27 Sep 1828., (355); 1s.(1p.)
  - Silsbee, Nathaniel, 1773-1850. A.L.s. to James Lloyd; Washington, 24 Dec 1826., (356); 1s.(4p.)
  - Simpson, Jonathan. A.L.s. to James Lloyd; [Boston] 29 Sep 1813., (357); 1s.(2p.)
  - Smith, Charles W. A.L.s. to James Lloyd; [Philadelphia] 27 Mar 1828., (358); 1s.(3p.)
  - Spence, Robert Traill. A.L.s. to James Lloyd; Baltimore, 24 Jun 1826., (359); 1s.(2p.)
  - Spooner, Phoebe. A.L.s. to James Lloyd; Boston, 15 Jan 1822., (360); 2s.(6p.)
  - Story, Joseph, 1779-1845. A.L.s. to James Lloyd; [Washington] 8 Mar 1824., (361); 1s.(2p.)
  - Strong, Caleb, 1745-1819. A.L.s. to James Lloyd; Boston, 26 Oct 1812., (362); 1s.(2p.)
  - Strong, Caleb, 1745-1819. MS.L.(copy) to Thomas Handasyde Perkins; [n.p.] 13 Oct 1814., (363); 1s.(3p.)
  - Sturgis, William, 1782-1863. MS.L.s. to James Lloyd; Boston, 26 Jun 1826., (364); 1s.(2p.)
    Also signed by Charles Sprague,; James Read,; Louis Draper,; Joseph T. Buckingham.
  - Sullivan, George, 1771-1838. 7 A.L.s. and MS.L.s. to James Lloyd, as follows:
    - Washington, 1 Jul 1823., (365); 1s.(3p.)
    - Same, 21 Nov 1823., (366); 1s.(3p.)
    - Same, 3 May 1824., (367); 1s.(3p.)
      with draft of Lloyd's reply.
    - Same, 18 Feb 1825., (368); 1s.(4p.)
    - Same, 21 Feb 1825., (369); 1s.(2p.)
    - Same, 21 Feb 1825., (370); 1s.(2p.)
    - Same, 22 Feb 1825., (371); 1s.(3p.)
  - Trumbull, John, 1756-1843. A.L.s. to James Lloyd; [Boston] 18 Jun 1823., (372); 1s.(2p.)
  - U.S. President, 1801-1809 (Jefferson) MS.L.s. to James Lloyd; Washington, 30 Dec 1808., (373); 1s.(1p.)
  - U.S. President, 1817-1825 (Monroe) MS.L.s. to James Lloyd; Washington, 19 Jan 1825., (374); 1s.(2p.)
  - Van Buren, Martin, pres. U. S., 1762-1862. A.L.s. to James Lloyd; Albany, 23 Aug 1822., (375); 1s.(3p.)
  - Vassall, Anne. A.L.s. to James Lloyd; Reading, 30 May 1821., (376); 1s.(4p.)
  - Wainwright, R. D. A.L.s. to James Lloyd; Washington, 3 Jan 1823., (377); 1s.(4p.)
  - Washington, Bushrod, 1762-1829. A.L.s. to James Lloyd; Mount Vernon, 9 Jun 1824., (378); 1s.(2p.)
  - Webster, Daniel, 1782-1852. 6 A.L.s. to James Lloyd, as follows:
    - Boston, 20 Dec 1819., (379); 1s.(3p.)
    - Washington, 16 Jul 1823., (380); 1s.(3p.)
    - Same, 17 Jul 1823., (381); 1s.(2p.)
    - [Same] 9 Oct [1823], (382); 1s.(3p.)
    - Same, 12 Dec 1826., (383); 1s.(4p.)
    - Same, 17 Mar 1827., (384); 1s.(2p.)
  - Wells, John. MS.L.s. to James Lloyd; Boston, 17 Jun 1826., (385); 1s.(2p.)
    Also signed by Jesse Putnam and J. Parker. With copy of public testimonial to Lloyd. 1s.(3p.)
  - Wheelers point. [Subscription list for well to be dug on Wheelers point] MS.s. (by various hands); Boston, 12 Jul 1811., (386); 1s.(2p.)
  - Shiston, Francis O. Printed letter s. to James Lloyd; Boston, 28 June 1826., (387); 1s.(2p.)
    Also signed by E. Wright Jr. and William Simonds.
  - Woolsey, Melancthon Lloyd. 1758-1819. A.L.s. to James Lloyd; Cumberland Head, 3 Feb 1818., (388); 1s.(4p.)
    Contains notes on Lady Hester Temple.
- VI. Letters from Senator Lloyd
  - 11 letters, etc., to John Adams, pres. U. S., 1735-1826.
    - Boston, 24 Jun 1813., (389); 1s.(2p.)
    - [Same] 26 Dec 1814., (390); 1s.(3p.)
    - Same, 6 Feb 1815., (391); 2s.(6p.)
    - Same, 15 Feb 1815., (392); 1s.(4p.)
    - Same, 23 Feb 1815., (393); 2s.(6p.)
    - [Same] 2 Mar 1815., (394); 1s.(2p.)
    - Same, 8 Mar 1815., (395); 8s.(30p.)
    - Same, 17 Mar 1815., (396); 2s.(6p.)
    - Same, 7 Apr 1815., (397); 4s.(16p.)
    - Same, [ ] Aug 1818., (398); 1s.(3p.)
    - Copies made by Lloyd of documents sent him by John Adams., (399); 3s.(5p.)
  - 1 letter to John Quincy Adams, pres. U. S., 1767-1848. Boston, 8 Oct 1825., (400); 1s.(2p.)
  - 1 letter to Samuel Appleton Washington, 18 Feb 1811., (401); 2s.(8p.)
    MS. copy by another hand.
  - 3 letters to John Borland.
    - Boston, 20 Feb 1821., (402); 1s.(4p.)
    - Washington, 6 Jan 1824., (403); 1s.(2p.)
      incomplete.
    - Philadelphia, 7 Oct 1830., (404); 1s.(4p.)
  - 1 letter to Rebecca Borland. Boston, 28 Sep 1828., (405); 1s.(2p.)
  - 1 letter to Samuel Breck, 1771-1862. Boston, 20 Aug 1817. 2 copies by different hands of the letter telling the adventures of John Lloyd., (406)
  - 2 letters to John Brooks, 1752-1825.
    - Washington, 23 Jan 1823., (407); 1s.(4p.)
    - Same, 3 Feb 1823., (408); 3s.(12p.)
  - 1 letter to John Caldwell Calhoun, 1782-1850. Boston, 1 Oct 1835., (409); 2s.(4p.)
    with another draft, 1s.(4p.) Letter resigning from the U. S. Senate.
  - 1 letter to C. E. Coe. Auburn, 14 Jul 1828., (410); 1s.(4p.)
    Letter complaining about stagecoach service; with contracts, etc., 3s.(8p.)
  - 8 letters to William Eustis, 1753-1825.
    - [N.p.] 21 May 1821., (411); 1s.(3p.)
    - Boston, 4 Jun 1822., (412); 1s.(4p.)
    - [N.P.] 7 Jul 1823., (413); 3s.(9p.)
    - [N.p.] 21 Jul 1823., (414); 1s.(4p.)
    - Philadelphia, 19 Nov 1823., (415); 1s.(2p.)
    - Washington, 10 Dec 1823., (416); 1s.(4p.)
    - Same, 28 Jan 1824., (417); 2s.(7p.)
    - Same, 20 May 1824., (418); 1s.(4p.)
      copy by another hand.
  - 2 letters to Edward Everett, 1794-1865.
    - Boston, 4 Oct [1824], (419); 1s.(1p.)
    - Same, 10 Oct [1824], (420); 1s.(1p.)
  - 1 letter to John Murray Forbes, 1771-1831. [N.p.] 11 Oct 1819., (421); 1s.(3p.)
  - 1 letter to William Charles Jarvis, d. 1836. Washington, 25 May 1826., (422); 1s.(3p.)
  - 5 letters to Levi Lincoln, 1782-1868.
    - Boston, [ ] Oct 1825., (421); 2s.(6p.)
    - Same, 1 Oct 1825., (424); 1s.(4p.)
    - Same, 1 Oct 1825., (425); 1s.(4p.)
    - Same, 12 Oct 1825., (426); 1s.(4p.)
    - Washington, 23 May 1826., (427); 1s.(4p.)
  - 1 letter to Thomas Handasyd Perkins, 1764-1854. [N.p.] Jul 1822., (428); 1s.(4p.)
  - 8 letters, etc., to John Randolph, 1773-1833.
    - Boston, 19 Jan 1815., (427); 35s.(35p.)
    - Washington, 5 May 1826., (430); 1s.(3p.)
    - [Same] 5 May 1826., (431); 1s.(1p.)
    - Same, 5 May 1826., (432); 1s.(4p.)
      A record of transactions with Bandolph, not a letter.
    - Same, 18 May 1826., (433); 2s.(4p.)
      A record of exchanges in the Senate, not a letter.
    - Philadelphia, 26 May 1826., (434); 1s.(2p.)
      A memorandum about Randolph, not a letter.
    - Same, 28 Dec 1827., (435); 1s.(3p.)
    - [Same? n.d.], (436); 1s.(3p.)
  - 1 letter to Edward Reynolds, 1793-1881. Philadelphia, 4 Dec 1827., (437); 1s.(3p.)
  - 1 letter to Benjamin Russell, 1761-1845. Washington, 7 Mar 1825., (438); 1s.(4p.)
    imperfect.
  - 1 letter to William Sturgis et al. [Boston] 28 Jun 1826., (439); 1s.(2p.)
  - 1 letter to George Sullivan, 1771-1838. Boston, 7 Jul 1823., (440); 2s.(6p.)
  - 1 letter to James Teacher. Boston, 16 Sep 1829., (441); 2s.(8p.)
    On the medical career of Dr. James Lloyd.
  - 1 letter to John Welles et al. Boston, 26 Jun 1826., (442); 1s.(4p.)
  - 1 letter to Melancthon Lloyd Woolsey, 1758-1819. Boston, 28 Jun 1815., (443); 1s.(3p.)
  - James Lloyd's notes on correspondence, etc., dealing with the Massachusetts claim. [Washington, 1824-1825], (444); 2s.(4p.)
  - [Lloyd, James, 1769-1831] Expense book. England, France, United States, 24 Sep-1 Aug 1791-1793. Original red calf., (445)
- VII. Borland correspondence
  - Abbot, Samuel Leonard. A.L.s. to John Borland; Boston, 31 May 1832., (446); 1s.(3p.)
  - Borland, Francis. A.L.s. to John Borland; Providence, 3 Sep 1824., (447); 1s.(2p.)
  - Borland, John. A.L.s. to William H. Aspinwall; Boston, 10 Jan 1835., (448); 1s.(2p.)
    Evidently a file copy.
  - Borland, Samuel. A.L.s. to Gardiner Greene; Demerara, 15 May 1802., (449); 1s.(2p.)
  - Borland family. Legal papers, 1839-1845. 1s. and 1 env., (450)
  - Holmes, Oliver Wendell, 1809-1894. MS.L.(copy) to [Julia (Gibson)] Borland; [Boston] 26 Nov 1862., (451); 1s.(2p.)
  - Jackson, Patrick Tracy, 1780-1847. A.L.s. to John Borland; Boston, 7 Apr 1835., (452); 1s.(2p.)
    With copy of Borland's letter to Jackson, 11 Apr 1835. 1s.(2p.)
  - Lloyd, James, 1769-1831. A.L.s. to Leonard Vassall Borland; Boston, 20 Oct 1799., (453); 1s.(4p.)
  - Loring, Robert R. 6 A.L.s. to John Borland, as follows:
    - Montreal, 21 Feb 1823., (454); 1s.(3p.)
    - Same, 9 Feb 1829., (455); 1s.(2p.)
    - Halifax, 13 Jun 1829., (456); 1s.(4p.)
    - Same, 2 Dec 1829., (457); 1s.(4p.)
    - Same, 29 Dec 1830., (458); 1s.(4p.)
    - London, 29 Aug 1838., (459); 1s.(4p.)
  - Penhallow, Benjamin. A.L.s. to John Borland; Portsmouth, 12 Jan 1824., (460); 1s.(2p.)
  - Sargent, Lucius Manlius, 1786-1867. A.L.s. to John Borland; Quincy, 22 Apr 1823., (461); 1s.(2p.)
  - Sparks, Jared, 1789-1866. MS.L.s. to John Borland; Cambridge, 25 Nov 1851., (462); 1s.(3p.)
- VIII. Membership diplomas
  - American academy of arts and sciences, Boston. [Membership certificate of James Lloyd (1769-1831)] Boston, 28 May 1811. Signed by John Adams,; John T. Kirkland,; John Farrar,; Josiah Quincy., (463)
  - American antiquarian society, Worcester, Mass. [Membership certificate of James Lloyd (1769-1831)] Worcester, 24 Aug 1820. Signed by Isaiah Thomas,; Rejoice Newton., (464)
  - American philosophical society, Philadelphia. [Membership certificate of James Lloyd (1728-1810)] Philadelphia, 20 Jan 1786. Signed by Benjamin Franklin,; John Erving,; William White,; Samuel Vaughan,; James Hutchinson,; Robert Patterson,; Samuel Magaw,; John Foulke., (465)
  - Humane society of the commonwealth of Massachusetts. [Certificate of membership of James Lloyd (1728-1810)] Boston, 27 Feb 1786. Signed by Thomas Russell and John Avery., (466)
  - Humane society of the commonwealth of Massachusetts. [Certificate of membership of James Lloyd (1769-1831)] Boston, 4 Apr 1803. Signed by John Warren and John Avery., (467)
- IX. Genealogical data
  - Genealogical data on the Temple, Nelson, Lloyd, Vassall, Borland, and allied families. 3 env. and 1 vellum scroll., (468)
- X. Newspaper clippings
  - Clippings, mainly from the Lloyd papers. 1 env., (469)
- XI. Pictures
  - Photographs of portraits of various members of the Lloyd family., (470); 9 pieces.
- XII. Deeds
  - Deeds of sale of the Borland family., (471); 12 pieces.